Like pretty much everyone
in the history of
YouTube, you probably hate
coming up with thumbnails
and titles because it's
so hard to get
a click. And years
ago, I was the
same. No one would
watch my videos. But
I mean, are you
surprised when I made
thumbnails a bit like
that?
Disgusting. But what I
had started getting good
at back then was
keeping people watching. Comments
were coming in like,
here before this channel
blows up and why
can't I stop watching
your videos? Usually means
you're making good content,
but your positioning and
packaging still needs work.
So I asked myself,
instead of using the
end screen to promote
some random video like
everyone was doing back
then, what if I
used it to hook
the viewer to watch
the next one? So
I tested my plan
and my end screen
click -through rates jumped
from 0 .9 %
to over 20%. What
that meant was 20
% of the people
who saw the end
screen watched another video.
And unless you're Mr.
Beast, it's pretty much
impossible to get a
click -through rate on
a video, on the
homepage or anywhere on
YouTube that's that high.
But also, once I
had 10 videos all
doing this, I mean,
crazy. When one of
them blew up, the
others in that stream
got dragged up with
it because people just
funneled through the end
screens. So this was
10 times more effective
and easier than trying
to get people to
click on a video
when it appeared anywhere
else on YouTube and
it was working. And
because we have to
warm viewers up by
getting them to consume
all of this content,
it means it was
10 times more effective
for sales too. And
this one system drove
over 700 ,000 views
on Film Booth and
on my current channel,
it generates almost as
many views as the
entire traffic source of
search. It's all because
of the end screen.
And it's also why
I do not worry
about when a video
flops. If I look
at my RevTrack data
and a video is
getting sales and emails,
but no views, I'm
like, yes, I have
a new sales tool
to point new videos
at from their end
screens. And when you
have 20 videos all
pointing at a video
that is converting, you
make more money even
if YouTube ain't pushing
it. And that's why
10 out of 10
flops don't matter so
long as you're using
RevTrack because we can
take control of the
views with our end
screens. So in this
video, I'm gonna show
you how to structure
your ending. To make
viewers click without begging.
I'm gonna give you
the exact system I
use and I'm gonna
show you how to
build a chain reaction
of views, watch times
and sales, even if
your videos don't go
viral. All right, so
let's start with this
in action. Thing is,
once you've shot this,
you then need to
edit it to make
sure you don't do
anything that puts buyers
off there. So watch
this video next, where
I'm gonna show you
the simplest editing system
in the world even
a beginner could do
and has helped me
make millions. All right,
so that was one
of my end screen
calls to action, but
what makes a great
ending? Let's break down
what's actually happening here.
So at its core,
a great ending does
one thing. It tells
the viewer exactly what
to do next and
makes them want to
do it fast. So
if you do this
right, your end screen
click -through rates will
go into the double
digits pretty easily. So
to make this happen,
I just have a
little three -part formula.
The first, I recap
the transformation. So basically,
I remind the viewer
in one sentence of
the value they got
that makes them feel
like the video delivered,
built trust and then
primes them to keep
going. So for example,
I might say, so
now you know exactly
how to build a
logic bricks that feel
clear, easy and inspiring.
And then I reveal
the problem that still
exists. So you tell
them what they just
learned isn't enough to
get the result they
really want by calling
out one of the
three big problems your
channel solves. This creates
urgency and makes it
clear if they don't
fix the next thing,
nothing's gonna work. So
for example, that might
sound like, but here's
the thing, your logic
brick will never turn
viewers into buyers unless
your intro hooks people
in the first place.
And then we move
on to the third
thing where we position
the next video as
the fix. This is
the moment the video
appears on screen and
you say something like,
so what's this video
next where I'll show
you exactly how to
write a click that's
gonna make people binge
your videos and buy
faster. That's it, there's
no begging, there's no
like and subscribe, just
a very confident, well
-positioned next step. But
how do you know
which video to link
to at the end?
Well, here's what not
to do. Don't try
and map out a
perfect chain of videos
in advance. It's gonna
drive you nuts. Instead,
I keep it simple.
I use two options
and I pick these
in under five seconds.
So option one, I
just look at my
RevTrack data and if
I'm creating a brand
new video, I ask
which of my past
videos converted best for
sales, emails or leads,
and then I will
just point to that
video. And then option
two is if I'm
repeating a video format
that worked before like
a roast or a
process, I just point
back to the previous
video that used the
same format and got
strong results. Now what's
important to know is
I don't just automatically
point to the previous
one that I made
of the same format.
If it underperformed, I'll
always link to one
that did get views,
sales or emails, right?
But what if this
is your first video
on the channel or
in this new system
or you've repositioned? Well,
don't link to another
video. Just say subscribe
and then put the
subscribe button. We all
have to start the
chain somewhere. And whatever
you do, please don't
link to a video
that you haven't made
yet. You're just gonna
confuse people and you'll
probably forget. And people
aren't gonna come back
and go, oh, I
wonder if that end
screen's there yet. So
when you build your
channel, in the way
that I teach, picking
the end screen should
be a 20, 30
second decision, Max, do
not overthink this at
all. But now I
need to give you
the golden rule for
ending a video. And
that is never end
a video. What that
means is never wind
down or use the
words and finally, or
never recap all the
lessons you taught at
the end. The goal
is to make a
video that's so good,
people don't even realize
it's getting to the
end. So think of
all your videos as
just one system that
connects, not individual entities
and just set up
the problem they still
have. And then point
them to another video
so the viewers don't
switch off. All right,
so that's the ending.
In the next video,
I'm gonna show you
how to optimize your
scripts for sales. And
email signups.